<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IMMERSE project website on IMMERSE project website</title>
    <link>https://immerse-ocean.eu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IMMERSE project website on IMMERSE project website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019-present IMMERSE consortium</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A simplified atmospheric boundary layer model for an improved representation of air–sea interactions in eddying oceanic models: implementation and first evaluation in NEMO (4.0)</title>
      <link>https://immerse-ocean.eu/publications/gmd-14-543-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://immerse-ocean.eu/publications/gmd-14-543-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Parcels v2.0 Lagrangian framework: new field interpolation schemes</title>
      <link>https://immerse-ocean.eu/publications/gmd-12-3571-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://immerse-ocean.eu/publications/gmd-12-3571-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new forum for the NEMO users community </title>
      <link>https://immerse-ocean.eu/post/2021-06-14-new-nemo-users-forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 08:23:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://immerse-ocean.eu/post/2021-06-14-new-nemo-users-forum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The need for setting up a new forum for NEMO users to share experience and tips was raised during one of the splinter sessions of our general assembly in March 2021. In response to this need, the NEMO system team opened a new forum on &lt;em&gt;discourse&lt;/em&gt; a week ago. Open 7 days ago the forum has already 57 registered users !  Thanks to the NEMO system team for its reactivity ! We are looking forward to share our experience with NEMO with you all on this new plateform !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nemo-ocean.discourse.group&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://immerse-ocean.eu/img/posts/immerse-nemo-users-forum-2021.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A session dedicated to NEMO development at vEGU2021</title>
      <link>https://immerse-ocean.eu/post/2021-04-26-virtual-egu-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 13:23:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://immerse-ocean.eu/post/2021-04-26-virtual-egu-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The IMMERSE consortium has organized a session dedicated to the numerical modelling of ocean circulation jointly supported by the NEMO consortium at vEGU2021. Several of the new developments to NEMO supported by IMMERSE have been presented during this vibrant session. We are now all looking foreward to meet again in person next year !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://meetingorganizer.copernicus.org/EGU21/session/39731&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://immerse-ocean.eu/img/posts/immerse-vEGU2021-session.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IMMERSE Virtual General Assembly on March 3-5, 2021</title>
      <link>https://immerse-ocean.eu/post/2021-03-10-virtual-general-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 13:23:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://immerse-ocean.eu/post/2021-03-10-virtual-general-assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project general assembly was held virtually on March 3-5. About 80 participants and key stakeholder have registered to our plenary sessions and splinter discussions. A great time for us to take stock of the project progress and refine our plans for the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://immerse-ocean.eu/img/posts/immerse-intro-slide_ga-2021.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IMMERSE General Assembly and review meeting on Dec 12-13, 2019</title>
      <link>https://immerse-ocean.eu/post/2019-12-15-general-assembly-and-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 13:23:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://immerse-ocean.eu/post/2019-12-15-general-assembly-and-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project General Assembly was held in Paris on 12-13 Dec 2019. We decided to gather at the same location and time as the NEMO System Team for its annual merge party. The first two years of the IMMERSE project indeed mostly consist in developments to the NEMO ocean model and this is why we articulate our agenda and activities with the NEMO consortium. The meeting consisted in a combination of talks reviewing the project progress and more in depth scientific presentations. See you all next year !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://immerse-ocean.eu/img/posts/immerse-agenda-general-assembly-dec2019.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D1.1 - Public website</title>
      <link>https://immerse-ocean.eu/deliverables/d1.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 16:18:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://immerse-ocean.eu/deliverables/d1.1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D1.4 -  Data Management Plan</title>
      <link>https://immerse-ocean.eu/deliverables/d1.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 16:18:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://immerse-ocean.eu/deliverables/d1.4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Webinar Downstream Toolbox</title>
      <link>https://immerse-ocean.eu/post/2019-04-07-webinar-downstream-toolbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 17:03:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://immerse-ocean.eu/post/2019-04-07-webinar-downstream-toolbox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On April 5th 2019, the IMMERSE Users Remote Workshop was held to introduce the IMMERSE interfaces to the CMEMS users community and coastal modellers, outside the project. The webinar was organized by CMCC Foundation and NOC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a brief introduction to present the IMMERSE project and the Task 7.3 by Dorotea Iovino (CMCC), Yann Drillet from Mercator Ocean presented CMEMS and its main actions on Marine Services &amp;amp; System Evolutions, and the structure of DIAS « WekEO ». WekEO is the EU Copernicus reference service for environmental data, virtual processing environment and skilled user support that IMMERSE aims to connect in the mid-term project implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stefania Ciliberti, Laura Stefanizz (CMCC) and Michaela De Dominicis (NOC) then presented the prototype toolbox framework for seamless uptake of CMEMS products in downstream monitoring systems. As a starting point, a number of tools/approaches currently used by CMCC and NOC research applications are shared within IMMERSE community, as PyNEMO (in use at NOC) and the SURF pre-processing interphase (in use at CMCC).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total, 131 experts registered to IMMERSE User Remote Workshop and 74 people from CMEMS community, research &amp;amp; academia, business sector and public authorities attended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A questionnaire for getting back feedbacks has been prepared and presented to users. Several questions have been raised by attendees, spanning from general information on CMEMS and the use of high quality products in models setup to specific information about numerical approaches for solving high resolution ocean-to-coastal processes and the use, by means of IMMERSE interfaces, of data from CMEMS and other international initiatives to improve the quality of downstream services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://immerse-ocean.eu/img/posts/immerse-interface-webinar_2019-04-05.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IMMERSE Kick-Off meeting on Jan 24-25, 2019</title>
      <link>https://immerse-ocean.eu/post/2019-02-10-project-kick-off-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 13:23:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://immerse-ocean.eu/post/2019-02-10-project-kick-off-meeting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IMMERSE project was officially launched on 24 and 25 January 2019 in Grenoble during the kick-off meeting with fourteen project partners. This kick-off meeting was an opportunity for the consortium to discuss the project methodology, the different activities to be implemented and the upcoming deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://immerse-ocean.eu/img/posts/immerse-group-photo-kom.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D1.5 - Outreach video</title>
      <link>https://immerse-ocean.eu/deliverables/d1.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://immerse-ocean.eu/deliverables/d1.5/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D2.2 - A reproducible protocol for sharing NEMO configurations</title>
      <link>https://immerse-ocean.eu/deliverables/d2.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://immerse-ocean.eu/deliverables/d2.2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D2.4 - NEMO v4.2_RC beta release</title>
      <link>https://immerse-ocean.eu/deliverables/d2.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://immerse-ocean.eu/deliverables/d2.4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D4.2 - Report on the performance of the coupling interface with BGC models</title>
      <link>https://immerse-ocean.eu/deliverables/d4.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://immerse-ocean.eu/deliverables/d4.2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D7.1 - Tools for estimating forecast errors</title>
      <link>https://immerse-ocean.eu/deliverables/d7.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://immerse-ocean.eu/deliverables/d7.1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
